<topics>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-statue-of-liberty</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026497/1878-04-17/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Statue+Harbor+Liberty+Lighting+World+Bartholdi</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The Statue for IKevr York Harbor.
				A French paper eaya The colossal
				statue of "Liberty Lighting tho
				World, erected by France and Ameri
				ca in remembrance of their old friend
				ship, is coming ont little by little from
				the immense workshops established
				expressly for its construction in the
				Kiie de Chazelle', No. 25, near Mon
				ceaux Park. The arm aud hand hold.
				ing the torch are already in America,
				and at present the sculptor. Bartholdi.
				is finishing the principal portion of the
				lioa.l IR. ill 1
				.v,.4, .J.UD iiu3bci uiuuei it ueariv com
				pleted. In a few days it will be strip
				ped of the Fcaffolding which surrounds
				ii ana upon which several gangs of men
				are at work. The first sentiment in
				spired by tho enormous head, nearly
				thirty feet high, is almost terror. Its
				gigantic dimensions are stupefying; but
				ujr uegrees mo eye Decomes accustomed
				to the colossal forms, and the mind
				reconciles itself to the extent of those
				great lines, and we discover in the midst
				of them the majesty and the light
				which the author has endeavored to give
				ti the features. But the publio will
				soon have an opportunity to see the beau
				ty of this work.for the head of the statue
				of Liberty is to be exhibited at the
				Universal Imposition.- Nevertheless,
				we strongly advise every one before-
				nana to visit the establishment on the
				Ruo de Chazelles and see how the dif-
				rerent portions of this head are prepared,
				worked nud adjusted. M. Bartholdi is
				making copies in plaster of his statue of
				liinerty. lwo huLdred of them only
				will bj executed, numbered and regis
				tered with the name of the niirnh
				who iany in this may preserve a souvenir
				or tmsniagnmcentcomniemorativeof the
				centennial anniversary of the independ
				ence of the United States, and destined
				to renew aud enliven the old friendship
				between franco and America.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014424/1881-10-11/ed-1/?sp=4&q=COLOSSAL+STATUE+Liberty+Bedloe%27s+Island+Bartholdi</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Tho Colosanl Kliitne of Liberty
				New York Times October 0
				Tho presence In Now York of tho French
				visitors to tho Yorktown celebration sug
				gests tho propriety of reminding tho Ameri
				can public of tho efforts which tho French
				nro making to keep alive- nnd pcrpctuato
				tho memory of tho disinterested friendship
				and generous aid given by Franco to tho
				colonics of North America in their strugglo
				for liberty nnd independence Sovcrnl
				years ago mi association was formed In
				Franco by somo of tbo most distinguished
				Eonubllcam with tlio titlo of Tho Franco-
				American Union under tho presidency of
				Americas special lrlcnii senator iiDouiago
				tho object of this association being to per
				notuato tho memory of tho friendship
				twecn Tranco nnd America by presenting to
				tho pcopl of tho United States a colossal
				statuo of Liborty to bo erected on
				Bedlbos Island in tho harbor of Now
				York and to servo as a beacon by moans
				of an electric light to bo placed In tho
				diadem on tbo head of Liberty Tho mate
				rial of tho statuo is hammered copper it
				will bo somo 120 feet In height aud was
				designed by and is being executed under
				tbo immcdlato direction of M A Bartholdi
				one of tho foremost of living scnlptcrs Tlio
				money for tho purposo was raised by volun
				tary subscription throughout France and
				tho work is steadily piogrcssing nnd will
				undoubtedly bo finished by midsummer
				18S3 A special act of Congress has given
				Bcdloos Island for tho purposo of tho erec
				tion of this statuo which is to bo placed
				upon a pedestal of masonry abotit 100 feet
				high A CDmralttco has been appointed
				Lore Under tbo chairmanship of tho Hon
				Win M Kvnrts to ralso tho necessary funds
				for tbo construction of tho pedestal and to
				have it built according to a design fur
				nished by tho sculptor and it Is contldcntly
				hoped that it will bo ready in timo for tho
				reception of tho statuo in 1883 And thus
				this glgantio monument willstand as nn en
				during manifestation of tho friendship bo
				tween tho two great republics of tbo world
				Diiulcl llooncM Nunkc</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075021/1885-05-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Liberty+Enlightening+World+Bartholdi+Statute</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Let LTh Good Work Go Os. Public sentiment hbar been thorough-ly aroused at last, ini favor of the move-ment toward the erecting of Bartholdl's statute, "Liberty Enlightening the World," inu the harbor of New York. Americans now understand that those among them who subscribe to the completion of this grand work, will perform an act of patriotism, and at the same time one of International comity worthy of the enlightened ideas permesting this nineteenth century. Some idea of the extent of the pub-lic sentiment is shown by the fact tbat the New York World has been able to report subscriptions of over $30,000 in a month's time, in sums averaging less than $1" each, the great bulk of these contributions being in dimes and quarters.
				What a aiagniflcent object it will be, towering almost into the clouds from New York's beautiful harbor! It will stand as a grand symbol of liberty be-fore the eyes of every one coiaiug frol l the oppressed countries beyond the ocean. At the gateway of no other nation oould it stand with such ap-propriateness. Here it symbolizes the fullest achievement of human freedom and will forever stand to tell that story.
				The committee in charge of the erec-tion of the pedestal for the reception of this great work have prepared a beautiful statuette, as a souvenir tb send to eob person who sab uilbe. -Ought not the beat of every Acan to respond with pride when he bas the opportunity of contributing toward the erection of such a monou-ment? It is one of the grandest undertak-ings of modern times and eminently fitting that it should be built from the hearts and pockets of our people.
				The committee does not believe the American people are indifferent to this great work, therefore calls upon them for their aid. Every person wishing to secome a sobscriber should soend their address to Richard Butler, Secretary American Committee of the Statue of Liberty, No. 88 Mercer street, New York, incloling $1, and will re-orive In return a mlnature reproduc-tion of this great work. While large subscriptions are aways desirable it would be far more to he credit of this great nation if evqtl man, woman and child should *ro *block In the pedestal wbi Wle ll spp/W the everlasting mosamelt of LIIIBAY ENLIOMTaRei s3 WORLD</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016187/1885-05-28/ed-1/?sp=8&q=BARTHOLDI+STATUE+Liberty+Enlightening+World+Wonder+Colossus+Bedloe+Island</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BARTHOLDI'S STATUE.
				Liberty Enlightening the World.
				This now Wonder of the World, which is
				now being loaded on the French transport lsere
				for shipment to this country, is tho largest
				statue in tho world. Somo idea of its magni
				tude may bo obtained from tho fact that 40
				persons found standing room within the head.
				A six-foot man standing on tho level of tho
				lip3 only just reached the eyebrow. Whilo
				workmen wero employed on the crown of her
				head they seemed to bo making a huge sugar
				caldron, and they jumped with caso in and out
				tho tip of tho nose. Fifteen pcoplo might sit
				round tho flame of tho torch, which elevation
				can bo reached by a spiral staircase within tho
				outstretched arm.
				Tho London Daily Ncics, in speaking of it,
				says It is out aud away the largest statue of
				modern times. Tho Colossus of Rhodes was
				nothing to it. It could carry tho 'Bavaria' or
				tho 'Hermann' in its arms. It towers to tho
				skies from tho yard of the Ruo do Chazelles,
				whoro it has been eight years in construction,
				and tho view from its coronet sweeps clear of
				the six-story hbuses and beyond tho walls of
				Paris."
				Tho weight of this stupendous statuo is 440,
				000 pounds, of which 170,000 pounds are cop
				per and tho remainder wrought-iron. It is
				expected to arrivo in New York about the 25th
				of May, whero it will bo erected ou Bedloe's
				Island, this being the location selected for it by
				Gen. W. T. Sherman, who was appointed by tho
				President to mako the selection. When placed
				in position it will loom up 305 feot above tide
				water, tho hight of tho statuo being 151.2 feet,
				that of tho pedestal 91 feet, aud foundation
				52.10 feet.
				This imposing statue, higher than tho enor
				mous towers of the great Brooklyn Bridge or
				the steeple of Trinity Church, which is tho
				loftiest in tho city of New York, higher, in
				fact, than any of tho colossal statues of anti
				quity by its rare artistic proportions, as well
				as by its stupendous dimensions, will add an
				other to tho Wonders of the World. A word
				should bo said of its artistic "merit. The pose,
				stride, and gesture, with its classic face, aro
				pronounced perfect; the drapory is both mass
				ive and fine, and in some parts is as dclicato
				and silky in effect asif wrought with a fino
				chisel on tho smallest scale.
				The committco in charge of the construction
				of the baso and pedestal for tho reception of
				this great work aro in want of funds for its
				completion, and have prepared a miniaturo
				statuct, an exact counterpart of tho original,
				six inches in hight, tho ilguro being made of
				bronze, the pedestal of nickel silver, which
				they aro now delivering to subscribers through
				out tho United States for tho small sum of $1
				each. Aside from its being a lasting souvenir
				of this colossal statue, it will ornament onr
				homes and bear testimony that wo have con
				tributed to tho completion of ono of the grand
				est works of&modcrn times. All remittances
				should bo addressed to, Richard Butler, Secre
				tary American Committee of the Statuo of Lib
				erty, No. 33 Mercer Street, New York. Tho
				committee aro also prepared to furnish a model,
				in samo metals, twelve inches in hight, at $5
				each, delivered.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040340/1886-11-05/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Liberty+Light+Statue+Bartholdi+Colossal+Bedloe+Island</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Ins Bartholdi statue of Liberty Enlight
				ening the World was unveiled on the Sth
				in the presence of the President, tho Cabi
				net and tho French visitors. Immense
				numbers participated in the procession in
				.New York, and it was calculated 1,000,000
				sightseers were present
				A new post-office in Dakota has just been
				named Bartholdi by the Post-olllce Depart
				ment
				Tun London Xeics does not think tho IJar
				tholdi statue will increase tho friendship
				between France nnd America.
				The French visitors to the Bartholdi
				celebration wero greatly annoyed by auto
				graph cranks.
				</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89064939/1878-09-18/ed-1/?sp=4&q=PARIS+LETTER+Liberty+Statue+Bartholdi+Colossus+Exhibition</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>OUR PARIS LETTER.
				The head of the new Colossus,
				*'Liberty," which is in future to
				light all nations into the harbor of
				New York, has produced a profound
				impression on the visitors to the
				Exhibition. It is placed on the
				left-hand side of the grounds of the
				Champ de Mar's, looking towards
				the Seine. The face is very fine
				somewhat resembling that of the
				Apollo Belridere, and the effect from
				the othr side of the grounds, two
				thousand feet off, or so, is remark
				ably grandL- For the first time a
				modern sculptor has achieved that
				in which the' Greeks seemed to fink?
				no difficulty whatever, namely, the
				necessary exaggeration of parts to
				produce effect at a great distance.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89064939/1885-07-29/ed-1/?sp=1&q=BARTHOLDI+GIRL+Liberty+Enlightening+World+Statue+Pedestal+Colossal</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BARTHOLDI BIG GIRL
				The Prejudices Met By a Canvasser for the Pedestal Fund.  
				The Bartholdi pedestal fund is nearly complete. The statue has arrived, and soon New York Harbor will be graced by the most magnificent colossal statue the world has ever seen: "Liberty Enlightening the World!" What a priceless blessing personal liberty is. It is the shrine at which people, ground under the heel of tyranny in the older worlds, worship with a fervency that Americans can scarcely realize. It is a principle for which Nihilists willingly die the death of dogs; and fit and proper it is that, at the very entrance of the Bay of New York, this emblematic statue should flash a welcome to the world.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1886-10-24/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Statue+Liberty+Bartholdi+Goddess+Bedlow+Island</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text> THE BIG STATUE OF LIBERTY  FINAL PREPARATIONS FOR UNVEILING
				The canvas mask that has hidden the face of the Goddess of Liberty since last Wednesday was taken off for an hour or two yesterday afternoon, as if in compliment to the immense crowd of visitors to Bedloe's Island. The steamer John Field, instead of reappearing as promised, was put through another course of repairs, and the little steamer Water Lily took its place, to the great delight of all who have to travel often to the statue's out-of-the-way site. The island itself looks fresher and cleaner than it has in weeks. The grandstand and the speaker platform are built along the parapets and are all set up. The barren parts of the grounds have been cleared and leveled on the top and sides. Grass seed has been sown all over, and it is beginning to sprout here and there. The unsightly old boards have been burned, and the loose stones and rubbish from the work have all been carted back to the gullies at the island's western end. The hammering still continues on the right arm and shoulder blade of the Goddess, but practically, the great figure is ready for unveiling at any time.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071854/1886-10-29/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Liberty+Statue+Grand+Bedloe+Island</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text> The Statue
				The statue which was unveiled today is entitled "Liberty Enlightening the World.The name was bestowed upon it by M. Bartholdi. The idea aimed at was the symbolization of the progress of civilization and the growth of freedom, as expressed in the republican form of government. It was also meant to perpetuate the friendship of the French and American nations, begun in revolutionary days when this country was struggling to throw off the English yoke. The height of the statue from the base to the torch is 151 feet, 1 inch. The total height from the foundation of the pedestal to the torch is 305 feet, 6 inches. From heel to top of the head, it measures 111 feet, 6 inches, and the length of the hand is 16 feet, 5 inches.  Its entire cost was about $700,000.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83032011/1886-11-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Statue+Liberty+Bartholdi+Goddess+Pedestal+Colossal+Bedlow+Island</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>THE STATUE OF LIBERTY: HOW IT WAS MADE AND PUT IN PLACE.  The New York Tribune thus recounts the history of the great work of M. Bartholdi, which was unveiled on Thursday of last week in the New York harbor. The history of the Bartholdi statue from its inception to its unveiling is a checkered one and goes back through all sorts of delays and difficulties for almost twenty years.It was, strangely enough, just at the close of the disastrous war with Germany and while the horrors of the Commune were still raging in Paris that M. Laboulaye, the founder of the French-American Union, first definitively broached his patriotic project of building in this country a joint memorial of the struggles of the French and Americans in the Revolution, and sent the young sculptor Bartholdi to the United States to find, if possible, some suitable and happy idea.The first suggestion of the statue, perhaps, dates still further back to a dinner given under the Empire by M. Laboulaye at his country house, "Glavigny," near Versailles.  </text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-american-female-pilots</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1911-07-24/ed-1/?sp=4&q=aeroplan+aeroplane+aeroplanes+bird+birds+Lady+Mathilde+Moisant</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
				You might think that a girl whose brother had been dashed to death In an aeroplane would be about the last girl to take up aeroplan-Ing as a profession. Not so with Mathilde Moisant. There are so few women now fly-ing that she may be said to be one of the first to go into the game. She is taking lessons daily at Min-eola, and expects before many weeks to be earning money as an aviator. Miss Moisant Is a handsome young woman, of the dark, Span-ish type, spirited in her speech and actions, and there seems little doubt that she will make good. She has all the necessary nerve, and while she is Btill in the "grass-cutting" stage of flying, she is learning very rapidly to guide and control her machine. "My brother John always told me," she says, "that to be a suc-cessful flyer meant to anticipate every move of the machine, and to be able to take steps to meet an emergency the Instant it occurred. That la what I am trying con-stantly to keep in mind." After John was killed, I vowed never to get Into an aeroplane again, but the old longing that I had always had, when I saw him fly, came back, until I was no longer able to resist It. My fam-ily has opposed me In every way, but I am determined. No Fear In Machine. "I think anyone can learn to fly, but I don't think everyone can learn to be a really great aviator, and that Is what I Intend to be-come. I think it is born In me. I have no feeling of fear when I get into a machine. I know I shall learn to do the things John did-, and perhaps more than he ever did." Although supposed to stick to the ground, Miss Moisant made a flight a few days ago, greatly to the surprise of her instructor, An-drew Haupert. She pulled the clutch without knowing it and shifted her planes so as to send the machine up in the air several feet. She landed as lightly as a bird. Miss Moisant has her brother's famous cat, "Paris-London," and he flies with her as he did with the ill-fated aviator who carried him across the channel. </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-10-17/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Aeroplane+aeroplane+bird+birds+Mathilda+Moissant</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text> 
				MERE EARTH BEINGS MARVEL AT MISS MOISSANT'S FLIGHT
				NEW YORK, Oct. 16. Miss Mathilda Moissant, at the aviation field in Mineola, Long Island, this evening made a flight which was as good as any since the spring. Friends from South America and France had come to the field, and it was for their benefit that she gave the exhibition.  
				Leaving the field, she arose 1,500 feet. [Special Dispatch to The Call] She flew across to Meadowbrook and Westbury, flew south, crossing the motor parkway, and kept on until she was over the Great South Bay.  
				On her return flight, when she flew over the field, she made several sensational dips, to the terror of her friends, who feared she was falling, but she alighted gracefully.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1911-11-01/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Ladies+lady+Mathilda+moisant</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>WOMEN AVIATORS TO FLY
				IN THE CITY OF MEXICO.
				They Will Show President MiKlero
				and Then Tour Country Be
				fore Coming Hack.
				Four women sailed to-day "n the Mal
				lory I.lnn steamer Impnsas for the
				Oty of Mexico, where th v are to give
				avlutlon exhibitions at the Inauguration
				of President Madcro, after which they
				plan an extended tour of M. xlco, cover
				ing many long diet an era tiefore the;,
				aeturn.
				Miss Mathldle Molsant Is to pilot one
				machine, with her elster, Hate Louise
				Molsant. ar. her passenger. -Ml- Harriet
				yulmby took with her Miss M. C Long
				Both young women have frequently
				been aeen In flights In the New YorK
				section.
				Copt. I'ntrlck Donald Hamilton went
				on the lAtnpusaa as escort for the
				yourg women.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062268/1912-04-21/ed-1/?sp=24&q=aeroplane+Blanche+Mathilda+Moisant+Scott</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>MATHILDA MOISANT, SISTER OF DEAD
				AVIATOR. MAKES HER: FAREWELL FLIGHT. Mathilda Molsant in monoplane and irf
				r Aviation costume.
				Wichita Falls,, 'Texas, April 20. Mi6s
				Mathilda Molsant. avlatrlx and sister
				cf John B. Molsant, who was killed In
				an aeroplane accident at New Orleans
				In December, 1910, all but lost her life
				iu her farewell flight which she made
				here recently. Her machine struck a
				ridge of earth Just outside the base
				1&11 park. It came down right side
				up with the young woman still In her
				scat, but the framework crumpled
				from the Impact. In an instant the
				wreckage was ablaze, and before the
				hvlatrlx could escape her clothing was
				in flames.
				Ihe fire was extinguished before
				she had sustained serious Injury, but
				the machine was totally destroyed.
				Miss Molsant was one of America's
				three women aviators, the other two
				being Miss Harriett Quimby and Miss
				Blanche Scott. Only Miss Quimby
				and Miss Moisant hold diplomas en
				titling them to fly at organised
				meets. All three women have made
				numerous exibltion flights, and until
				the accident here the other day all
				could boast that they had never had
				a real smashup. Miss Moisant's ex
				perience here will probably make her
				more determined than ever not to re
				turn to the aviation field.
				For flying purposes Miss Moisant
				adopted the knickerbocker costume.
				She is small and dark.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058140/1910-05-29/ed-1/?sp=22&q=Blanche+lady+Scott</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-01-19/ed-1/?sp=32&q=aeroplane+Blanche+lady+Scott</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>LADY VIATORS' SPIRIT
				'GOES "UP IN THE IR"
				New York, Jan. 19. War has
				broken out among the 'avatrices"
				of America, and war. among the
				female of the species is more
				deadly Oh, much more deadly,
				than ,war among the male
				Charges of being a "grass cut
				ter" which in air language is
				equivalent to one colored gentle
				man telling another that a yellow
				streak runs up and down his back
				are being bandied across the
				1 continent. And rouge is not nec
				essary to redden the wrathy
				cheeks of the birdwomen.
				c Miss IBanche Scott, now in
				Los Angeles, began it. Miss
				Scott 'is not the possesor of an
				aviator's license, and perhaps she
				thinks she has been discriminat
				ed against in this matter. A r
				Anyway Miss Scott, she up
				and said 'that Miss 'Harriet
				Quimby and Miss Mathilde Moi
				sant who. be it noted, possess
				aviator's' licenses were afraid to
				qompete with -her, because she
				was. too daring and spectacular"
				for them.
				r When this was reported to Miss
				Harriet Quimby, that lady drew
				a long breath and assumed a
				s'cornfnl look.
				"Of course, she began, in icy
				tones, "you must understand that
				Miss Blanche Scott has never
				been awarde'd a license by the In
				ternational Aero club.
				"Under these circumstances, it
				is impossible for me, who has
				b'een -awarded a license, to chal-Jenge-
				her.
				"Otherwise"! should not hesi-
				tate to challenge Miss Scott
				"fie sides, this Miss Scott can
				nofdo the 'right hand turn.' That
				is 'one of the hardest things to do,
				and necessitates a1 spiral glide.
				I can do it.
				"The idea of Miss Scott saying
				that I am afraid to compete with
				her is too ridiculous to talk about
				I am not afraid of her, nor of any;
				man. Why, if I had the same pow
				er aeroplane 3S1 Claude Grabame
				White, I should not hesitate to
				challenge him for a race.
				"I don't believe hvthis circus
				flying. But 'I'm certainly not
				afraid of Miss Scott
				"Now if only she were.prqperly
				licensed, I should but .what is
				the use of talking she is NOTi
				licenced."</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85059715/1912-02-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Blanche+ladies+Scott&st=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>1 NERVIEST WtfMAN lN T
				WHAT BIRDMEN CALi
				I,
				IB
				7 ISL^NCMElSCoXl
				Mlsa Blanche Scott, the only vomai
				Los Angraloi and Oakland, Cal., meets,
				noted rblrdmcn who flaw In, competltk
				.an In the" business." SfieY swept up In
				only a four minutes after Tom Qunn, tl
				Oakland and narrowly escaped death.
				bad no visible effect on her spirits,</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053157/1912-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7&q=aeroplane+Blanche+Scott&st=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BLANCHE STUAR T SCOTT.
				Aviatrice Who Will 7 y to Fly Twice
				Over vHe En gl is-.i Channel.
				Blanche Stuart Scott, since Harriet
				Quimby's death America's only profes
				sional aviatrice, has auuouuced her in
				tention of not merely duplicating but
				of doubling Miss Quimby's successful
				Sight across the English channel. Miss
				Scott will start from Dover In au ef
				fort to fly to Calais in a h.vdroaero
				plane and return.
				Miss Scott has not been influenced
				by Miss Quimby's tragic death, which
				K
				It;
				MISS BLANCHE 8TITAHT SCOTT.
				she witnessed from her aeroplane, to
				entertain any fears of ber own ability
				to escape a like fate.
				"A death is only an Incident in the
				development of the science." she says,
				"and pioneers have died in the early
				struggles of all causes. It remains for
				those who are left to keep on striving
				for the ultimate triumph for which
				those who died gave up their lives."</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93055779/1911-07-26/ed-1/?sp=3&q=aeroplane+Aeroplane+bird+Blanche+Lady+lScott</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>First Women To 'Drive Aeroplane Cross Country In New World
				Many aviators and other air enthusiasts are congratulating Miss Blanche
				Stuart Scott of Rochester, N. Y who drove an aeroplane across county in a twelve mile flight from
				the aviation field here in ten minutes. Miss Scott is the first woman to achieve such a feat in America.
				She ftew. one of Captain Thomas S. Baldwin's biplanes, overtaking a, mere man aviator who' had started
				first, circled over the village of W 'stbury and returned to the field, making a safe landing. Miss Scott
				once drove an automobile all the w.vv across the continent. She is a pupil of Captain Baldwin and has
				made several trial flights on the aviation field.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1917-12-12/ed-1/?sp=3&q=aeroplane+Katherine+ladies+lady+Stinson</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
				SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 1. Miss Katherine Stinson, Texas aviatrix who started from San Diego at 7:31 a.m. today on a non-stop flight to San Francisco, reached her destination at 4:39 p.m. today. She was the first person to pilot an aeroplane over the Tehachapi mountains on a non-stop flight.The distance between San Diego and San Francisco on an airline is 461 miles. The distance Miss Stinson traveled was unofficially announced at 550 miles, which breaks the non-stop record held by Miss Ruth Law, who flew from Chicago to Hornell, N.Y., a distance of 512 miles.Miss Law was compelled to alight at Hornell by engine trouble. It was said by officials of the Pacific Aero Club that an official check could not possibly reduce the distance traveled by Miss Stinson by more than 10 miles.  
				Miss Stinson had been in the air nine hours when she alighted, and she showed the tremendous strain under which she had labored. Miss Stinson landed at the Presidio, a military reservation, by special permission.  </text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-marie-curie/selected-articles</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88068010/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Curie+radium</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Another cw Klement.
				Three French chemists M. and
				Mine, Curie and M. Bemont have dis
				covered a new metallic element, which
				they call "radium," because of its re
				markable property of emitting rays
				which resemble in their penetrative
				power Prof. Roentgen's celebrated X
				rays. Not long ago much surprise was
				caused by the discovery that uranium
				is capable of emitting similar rays, but
				the power of radium in this respect is
				Eaid to be 900 times greater than that
				of uranium.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-12-31/ed-1/?sp=23&q=Curie+Curies+radium</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The discovery of the new element is due to M. and Mme. Curie and is the result of investigations stimulated by the discovery of the X-ray. They were experimenting in 1898 with uranium and its salts, which exert a feeble photographic power, when they observed phenomena indicating the existence of an unknown factor in the mass. They at once directed their investigations to the separation of that element from the substances with which it was associated and found not one but two new elements. To the first, they gave the name "polonium" and to the second "radium." The first is believed to have a radiant power five hundredfold greater than that of uranium, but Professor Barker estimates the efficiency of radium at one hundred thousand times that of uranium. For this reason, and because of its comparative cheapness and simplicity, the second of the Curies' discoveries seems destined, it is said, to replace the costly and complicated X-ray apparatus in the realm of surgery.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1899-12-17/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Curie+Curies+polonium+Polonium</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
				The investigations of M. and Mme. Curie, which resulted in the finding of radium, began early in M. Curie's career, if not before, and were undoubtedly stimulated, if not directly created, by the brilliant achievements of Rontgen. Rontgen's work naturally called to mind the observations of Becquerel that uranium and its salts exerted a very feeble photographic influence. By experimenting with pitchblende, the mineral from which uranium is obtained commercially, M. and Mme. Curie found that the former yielded the same effect much more conspicuously. This led them to suspect that they were on the track of a new element. They even went so far as to name it provisionally, although much difficulty was experienced in separating it from the substances with which it was combined. Just before the close of the year, with the co-operation of M. Bemont, they isolated in positions still another new element. The first they called "polonium," and the second "radium." Polonium is believed to surpass uranium and its salts in emissive power five hundredfold, but Professor Barker estimates the efficiency of radium at one hundred thousand times that of uranium. For this reason, and because of its comparative cheapness and simplicity, the second of the Curies' discoveries seems destined to replace the costly and complicated X-ray apparatus in the realm of surgery.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069457/1900-03-08/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Curie+RADIUM+radium</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>A New Chemical Which Is Better
				Than the X Ray
				Prof Ri orgc F Barker of the phy
				sical laboratory of tho University of
				Pennsylvania exhibited lut week for
				the first time In America the newly
				discovered chemical element radium
				which seems destined to create a groat
				stir In the scientific world Yearn ago
				Bequercl found that Halts of the ruie
				metal uranium posesirod the power of
				throwing off a feeble and Invisible ra
				diance like the X rnys Mine Curie In
				lnrls last year Isolated from the Bo
				hemian mineral pltchblend two other
				elements that hehavc In tho Mime man
				ner but are far more active One of
				them she called polonium anil tho
				other milium The latter Is said to
				be 100000 times as Intense as uranium
				In Its photographic effect</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085421/1907-05-13/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Curie+Marie+Sklodowska</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The First Woman Professor In the
				Famous Sorbonne University at
				Paris. A slender, youthfnl woman in deep
				mourning, ber fair hair swept plainly
				back from a remarkably broad, high.
				full brow, her head seemingly almost
				too large for the slim neck that car
				ried it. her manner so simple, so un
				conscious and sincere that it was child
				like such was the appearance of Mmc
				Curie as she stood in a class room de
				livering the first lecture ever given by
				a woman professor to the students of
				the University of Paris. It was an
				event which should make women all
				over the world rejoice and take cour
				age, because at last the earnest, de
				voted scientific work of one of their
				MME.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1910-05-15/ed-1/?sp=14&q=Curie+CURIE+Marie+Sklodowska</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>MME CURIE, DISCOVERER OF RADIUM AND P0L0NIUM. The fame acquired some years ago by Mme. Marie Sklodowska Curie by her discovery of radium promises to be equaled, if not surpassed, by the honors which have come to her as the discoverer of the new, more wonderful element, polonium. It was as a coworker with her husband, the late Professor Curie, that this brilliant woman succeeded in isolating radium, and it is now with the assistance of M. de Bierne that she has succeeded in isolating the tenth part of a milligram of polonium. This substance, 5000 times rarer than radium and taking its name from her native Poland, was the product of the chemical treatment of more than five tons of pitchblende with hydrochloric acid. Polonium "wastes away" with great rapidity, a thousand times quicker than radium. Of course, the value of this discovery is as yet purely scientific in a theoretical sense.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045396/1911-12-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Curie+Marie+Nobel+NOBEL+prize</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
				Mme.Marie Curie Receives Nearly $ 40,000for Her Work in Chemistry. STOCKHOLM, Dec 10. King Gustav today presented the Nobel prizes, with the exception of the peace prize, to the winners. Mine A. Favrie Sklodowska Curie personally received the prize for chemistry; Professor Wilhelm Wien of Wuerzburg University the prize for physics, and Professor Alvar Gullstrand of Uppsala University the prize for medicine. The Belgian minister received the prize for literature on behalf of Maurice Maeterlinck, who is ill. The Nobel prize each amounted to nearly $4 ft.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Curie+Marie+NOBEL+Nobel+prize+Prize+Prizes+prizes</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>WOMAN WINS NOBEL
				CHEMISTRY AWARD
				Mme. Curte, Discoverer o! Ra
				dium and Polonium, Given
				$40,000 Prize
				STOCKHOLM. Nov. 7.—The Nobel
				prize for chemistry has been awarded
				to Mme. Marie Sklodowska Curie of the
				University of Paris.
				Mme. Curie is the chief professor of
				sciences in the University of Paris. She
				was the discoverer, with her husband.
				Prof. Pierre Curie, of radium, and in
				1903 shared with him half of the Xobel
				pflze for physics, the other half being
				awarded to Prof. Antoine Henri Bec
				queret. Each of the five Nobel prizes
				awarded annually amounts to $40,000.
				Recent announcement was made of
				the success of Mme. Curie in producing
				polonium, "a new element possessing a
				radio activity superior to radium."</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1912-05-02/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Curie+DISCOVERIES+discoveries+Discovery+Marie+radium</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>MME. C URIE. NOTED FRENCH SCIENTIST,
				WINS NOBEL PRIZE FOR DISCOVERIES. Marie Curie the great French scientist, who with her husband discovered radium. Mme Curie is without doubt the greatest of all women scientists. She was recently the recipient of the Nobel prize for her wonderful scientific chemical discoveries.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1921-04-05/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Curie+Marie+radium</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>AN IMMORTAL WOMAN
				The visit of Madam Marie Curie to this country in May
				will be celebrated by American women with the presentation
				of a thimbleful of radium to the distinguished scientist. At was
				a beautiful tribute to the modesty of womankind that Mine.
				Curie made when she discovered the element which has revo-
				lutionized physics, chemistry and some branches of medicine,
				and gave it an impersonal name. The courtesy of the labora-
				-tory dictates that the discoverer of a new thing under the sun
				may give it his own name if he wishes, and so perpetuate nia
				own glory. Mme. Curie called it radium, because it gives out
				HINTS TO GARDENERS
				More than sentiment attaches to the gift. Of course, it
				money value, something like $100,000, will have little weight
				with a devotee of science like Mme. Curie.: She will use the
				radium for scientific research. Although Mme. Curie knows
				more concerning radium and its potentialities than any living
				soul, she has not, because of her generosity, one grain with
				which to conduct experiments.
				The history of the discovery of radium is one of the most
				exalted romances that the world has ever known. The daugh-
				ter of a professor in the University of Warsaw, the present Mme.
				Curie was drawn to Paris by the magnetic pull of the renowned
				scientific schools there. In conjunction with the scientists
				Becquerel and Curie, she began a series of experiments with
				uranium which led to her discovery of radium. It also led to
				her happy marriage with Professor Curie. That the discovery
				was that of Mme. Curie alone was well established by a com-
				mission which awarded her the Nobel prize in 1903.
				The hope which radium holds out to the world is that it
				may be the means of fighting cancer, that malignant disease
				which has baffled physicians for centuries. Undoubtedly there
				are new fields into which researchers can go. And it is in these
				unexplored regions that Mme. Curie will venture. The women
				of America honor themselves by providing the means.</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
</topics>
